We'll now call one of the regular meeting of the Mauna City Council Monday,
for which we're going to the second twenty-one month, but we'll give that to them
to give them the first one of the branches, and we'll think we're adding five of them.
Number three, consent agenda.
Step at the end of the group, five, four, five.
And we'll move to the second.
We'll move to the final.
Number three, consent agenda.
Four, five, six, four, five.
The two claim to the group are the five.
I don't know the same.
So I can say, I guess I'll restake myself earlier.
So these claims that are in your back end, that's why I did mention,
very interesting.
These were pretty silly have been done last week, very important,
and basically another myth.
We were unable to have council meeting, and so tonight we're not free, and we can move forward with payments and other clubs in the city,
that for ordinance myself and Mayor are able to approve those claims.
So myself, the mayor, which is calling that the telephone, with room all of the claims in your packet,
and we're going to review them, and then they recognize us to approve them, and we're going to afford the city operations.
Knowing that they would come back, we're going to fill in the bill, and you can come to that.
So those are the claims that we're in the packet.
Okay, okay.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Are you ready?
I'm ready.
Excuse me.
Second.
The last time.
Oh, yes.
Is that.
I'm.
Great.
The business and the business of the residents of the business of the agenda.
Step reports.
Jim there at council meeting.
The mountain.
But I have to say that.
Thank you.
I'm Christian Church and we like to ask you in church, or.
Step down this week to be.
Shelter's acts for our homeless.
Let's list for.
Peter.
One of my issues.
have been picked around cross for green costs,
but other local people who stepped up,
brought food, cash, and classified,
and how they're into the church,
and just those folks come.
But we'll say, do this lead.
I said on several calls with our city manager,
and part of the heads, and I actually got to see
it in action, and I don't know yet,
but I don't see a situation.
And we did not stay in the office by our low-reson,
did I see a manager watching an action lead,
like he did, do that, to watch our apartment heads,
him delegated to the apartment heads,
and then the once or ten of the action,
it was pretty cool to watch.
And all the way down to the guys playing the streets,
you know, everybody did not stay in the job,
and I was proud to be part of the, you know,
you know, I've just got set there a list of a lot.
I actually see,
there was a new emotion that didn't take care of it.
So I appreciate it, as well as the city staff,
and all you used this week,
so it was a new offer to our citizens.
11, City Manager of the Education.
Well, first of all, we'd like to really piggyback
on one of some of the mayor's sentiments.
It was a very interesting, rough, unique last week,
with unprecedented weather that many others have not seen in their life.
No doubt that there were events that were taking place
and are very hard to prepare as someone trying to take care
of their family or as us working to the city,
trying to take care of citizens and divisions.
And the operations that we support, obviously,
you know, running, running the interesting challenge.
We thought diesel motors were hard to run
and you know, cold temperatures.
You could have in sub-zero temperatures,
and they're almost impossible.
But the teams were rallying tremendously.
It was extremely impressive for someone new
to mind the city government.
To see these teams jump into action,
deliver hesitate of moment, to jump into the digital water,
to dig up a broken warming, to grab a fire nose
and be involved in water, spray, and still fighting fires
having our folks, or the security responders out,
is a weather in the elements, no matter the situation,
is still respond.
And our folks in the office.
stepping up, working the hours, communicating. Everybody was so focused on the job of
the end and community. It really went so far our technology going to do. The city runs
with the Microsoft Teams. We were able to jump on the video communication multiple times
throughout the day and that was every city represented. Communicating across the work,
working doing the public safety, working doing the streets. What we're doing with our
public building, our library and the coal. We talked about, you know, the water, water
conservation, utilities, and electric, we had a constant conversation and all the situations
with the electric. But the entire team was in trouble. We did it quickly, and then we
could wrap up each one of those calls with what is the communication in the public and when
we capture all those notes and then our cheating police, the XC, the jump on social media,
and broadcast the message out on that regular basis. That became quickly a central point for us
as a thing to be able to communicate with our system and the status of our rows or streets,
whether as well as our in the situation with utilities. Everybody had a fantastic job and I couldn't
be more proud. The hour you were putting in, we started this actually the weekend before
and started having meetings over the weekend preparing. One day was a holiday, lots of clothes,
and we continued to have meetings. And throughout the week, we were having specific strategic
office closure. That's something else that I wanted to kind of talk about was the office closure
of those conversations. That was not something that was taken lightly. Because some of
our offices are in the area in which citizens engage with their city government who don't want to be available.
And we never want to not be providing services to our citizens. So in those conversations we were able to quickly discuss,
we talked a lot about a central and non-sensitive personnel, folks knowing who's expected to be
in the office or at work in a car truck, operating equipment, making sure the services are being done.
We had staff there all ready to tell them because of COVID. So we have to step ahead of the game and we will utilize those folks and they can do
working throughout the week, even though the office is proposed, they were going to tell what
in front of our homes, operating normal city operations. So thanks for being done.
One of the things we wanted to very closely was closing up.
the customer service like that's one area in which we know citizens make them in the
community for paying a bill directly or anything.
We know we have six other banks across town that are seven bankers, we have Dropbox.
We can go and drop off the bankers as well, they have online payments, and we have
a lot of background.
So for the most part, things kept looking right on for we also could be very
a lot of the situation we were having with power conservation departments.
We had Jared and you know requesting that we need the power conservation
logo that happens in businesses and it's quite a tricky process to see.
To shut down those policies, so taking those things into effect and we weren't adding them all of that.
But just being here, there's a team that looked at what operations were opening.
So rather than coming in into trying to stop them from seeing what building to cross town,
I don't know, wasn't necessarily, not to mention we had some interesting challenges
with the heat in this building, well, I know, the officers, my officers, then the office,
and the mother offices were down in the foys, and during the week, because the ACU was not able
to keep up in the temperatures that we were, so here, it wasn't even the most comfortable
to be, but honestly, things couldn't click back, the team stepped up, everybody was
able to keep things down, I never felt like city operations were being a warrior, and I was
being defeated, but as anticipated from that aspect, I think it was really not to say, we're
not just a lot of love this week, we've already got one scheduled to do a plus more of a million
day, but I knew lessons weren't, I think we wanted to bring them to the day, and discussed
what we think we could do better next.
The noise rates were up and up and up and up and up and up and up and up and up and up and up and
up and up and up and up and up and up and up and up and up and up and up and up and up and up and up.
That being said, you know, less of your point of huge thanks to our partners across the city
and the step-up, we were able to provide shelters, and I think we consistently felt like we had
a capacity where it would be the needs of their rows, and we had partners in the means
of radio, and up and doors, and we had been backstaffed, and we went to the city, those folks
just kept things like stepping up as the new rows, and so, as anticipated as the community
responded, you know, that's fine, all we've done, and that being said, I mean, it's probably
a new part of it, we've watched this team, and it's probably all great, I think we'll
work a lot for this experience, and the community is a talent, and the sector is less and more
and more.
And hopefully we get our happens experience at the end, but it will make us stronger, and I think it's better
From a communication perspective, we tried to really use all the different channels that were
able to us from social media, to our websites, we did broadcast telephone messages,
and we are building a system as well as text messages, but one of the things we don't
have that are supposed to look really trying to better utilize is in text, text, and
you know, a system that is offered through our hosting provider, our website.
Unfortunately, the utilization was pretty low, you know, we had about the 700 incisions
signed up for that service, but one of the things we did is, the opportunity is
last week, we were broadcasting our messages through our call system, the program
and the assistance of what drives you to go side up for that system.
We're going to continue to push that and hope that we can really drive an option.
We can go to our website, sign up for that word system.
We've actually looked at our licensing permission, we have our license in place,
since we did that, and if we can give more citizens signed up for that service, then we will
have a great flexibility in the capability so that we can better communicate
out the broadcast, push messages, and citizens.
In most cases, it may be as simple as a text message, pointing them to your website,
which is pretty much something that we're letting you get a current information.
So we hope to see more of that information, and hopefully we'll see more roads,
and we'll have to fill on that, and once to a high, and we can see the number check out
in the background.
Other than that, I think that's really probably everything I have at this time.
So I'm going to answer your questions.
Thank you.
I'm 12, and maybe we'll be continuing from the blanket room.
And we're going to begin with the staffing for the purposes of the executive session.
15.
You can go to the discussion about the act of the right committee.
The utility bill.
Right.
There was a very different session.
There was no action as taken.
And that's in the end of our relationship with a summary of the executive session.
So in the executive session, we discussed a couple items.
The council one was the estimation of consumption.
And this refers to our casting show.
It's a little important.
And the statement I would like to read involves there will be areas we will have to estimate.
So I slow our team was blocking those covering leaders and blocking the indexes, making this
to logistically impossible. It is our goal to stay in target letters and call our customers
effective. This is never ideal, and as we understand, we can cause customer frustration
with the tropchoccurry and mutual value of the state.
Estimations like that would be lower than what was actually new during this moment. So we have
to be able to possibly be advised to be accustomed to the best of a new reading. There was
time to pay extra to the anticipation of the intruder in the following words.
Additionally, to the disadvantage of the benefits of the average number of people playing
in our day of the market. In England, you can sign up to the course, the more history
of the better, the better. If low history is available, the best version of this cost, the cost
of the term in what opportunity to invest in the country needs such a way.
We budgeted fund and resources for normal, for norms and fees, not being sectioned by hearing
and issues in 12-inch plus countries. Realistically, given our current infrastructure and making
process, give the cost to the insistence of the state of the state of the way just in case we have
under a year when it should be. So when it does happen, the best we just want together to work through it
together. That was our discussion in the captain of some of the comments in the
simplest, probably in the captain. The second thing we are about was the utilization of the
system. So citizens and businesses must bring their higher bills into significant
increases in utilization, in addition to the potential for cost and increase in power,
generation, and passed on to the state. GRDA has a great stabilization fund.
How much they will use in this fund and the impact it will have on our cost to purchase electricity
and the coming funds is not yet known. GRDA has stated they will have information to share with
customers by the March approach. The city already has offerings to support customers.
The utility bills that we are building in the deal with, we currently offer the effort with the plan.
We also have the contract to pay out the amount of time. We also have been working to coordinate the local
materials, and the offering, and utility systems programs.
Concentration continues to be a key to public. We must not do as much.
We can't continue to increase our utilization and the ongoing energy crisis.
In of course, as we say, learn the information from GRDA.
or the state, or the separation permission of anyone else
to have an impact on the situation.
We're going to be in the put-by information
after some of the positions.
The position we're in today is you're trying to be in the response
of what's possible and shared with you, no questions.
Without creating a campaign for your information,
we don't have to.
We've been pushing them to make it a basis
in a year and a day, Tyler, and we're calling them to you.
Trying to make it a basis.
We've seen the role of the pressure of information
on our health, and to another press conference.
Today, we've got a relation to mention from Secretary of Agriculture.
And, you know, our part is trying to really drill down
another thing in how it impacts us this is,
the environment of the power of the consent of the union,
and how it's upstream and why we're having that effect
if we're all being able to see the impact.
We are just concerned about the effect that we have.
But the best thing we can do right now,
which is all we can do with these traits,
and we can do it today, and we can do well.
So that's what we're going to do.
I'm not going to tell you that.
I'm going to tell you that.
So, ladies and gentlemen.